Hello everybody. It's high noon in old
Cheyenne. I'd like to call the February
3rd, 2026 meeting of the finance
committee to order. Uh if you're in the
room, please silence your uh electronic
devices. If you're online and you want
to make a comment, use the raised hand
function
um in person, approach the podium,
remove your hat to address the
committee, and there will be no
additional business following the
completion of our agenda today. And all
communications go through the chair.
With that, Burke, you can read the first
item. Number 18 C. Lease agreement
between the city of Cheyenne and the
Girl Scouts of Montana and Wyoming for
45.93
acres of city-owned real property
located near the former Roundtop water
treatment facility to be used for the
purposes of conducting activities
consistent with the bylaws and articles
of incorporation of the Girl Scouts of
Montana and Wyoming.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chair Jason Sanchez, Community Wreck
and Events. Before you and for your
consideration is a multi-year lease
agreement between the city of Cheyenne
and the Girl Scouts of Montana and
Wyoming. Uh this is not a new uh lease
agreement. We've uh leased this property
camp Carefree to the Girl Scouts for
decades. U they've been good stewards.
They've been good partners. They help
maintain the area. Um, this lease uh we
we went into a one-year lease last year
with them because we were unsure of the
with the construction and the
possibility of uh partnering with the
state to create a state historic site.
That didn't happen and so we are
entering back into a multi-year lease
which is five years with an option to
renew five for an additional five years.
Um the the lease amount is $100 a year
and again these folks have been great
partners and good stewards of the area.
Uh staff recommends support and I'm here
to answer any questions.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee?
Councilman Wolf.
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, thank you Mr. Sanchez.
Um what what buildings are out there?
>> Mr. Chair, through you to Councilman
Wolf. Um on the north side of Roundtop,
we do have uh it's called Camp Carefree.
There's a building that the Girl Scouts
occupy and then there's a camp area that
they utilize as well. There is an
outdoor restroom facility there. Um, not
many people have seen it, not many
people have used it. Uh, but it's a very
nice area.
>> Further comments or questions from the
committee?
>> Any further public comment?
>> Can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve an
amount of $100 annually for the period
of five years.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman Moody, seconded
by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussion?
>> Councilman White.
>> None.
>> Ready for vote. All those in favor,
please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that that motion is carried
unanimously.
Recommendation to the governing body.
Next Monday will be to approve. Next.
Next item.
>> Number 19A. Contract modification number
one to contract number 811
between the city of Cheyenne Office of
Youth Alternatives and the Laramie
County Juvenile Services Joint Powers
Board for a juvenile diversion
coordinator to provide diversion related
services to increase the potential
contract dollar amount.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chair, committee members, good
afternoon. Jay Sullivan, the director of
youth alternatives. Uh, as uh was
stated, this is a a contract amendment
uh with the Joint Powers Board for
additional funding revenue to the city
in the amount of $78,000
uh for the diversion program. These
funds will uh allow us to hire an an
additional uh case worker uh to
facilitate the uh the increase in cases
coming through the district attorney's
office on diversion. Uh these cases
typically are ED neglect cases uh and
whatnot. Uh, with that, I'll stand by
for any questions. Thank you.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee?
>> Any public comment?
>> Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve an
amount of $78,175.65.
>> Second.
It's been moved by Councilman Moody,
seconded by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussions or comments?
Seeing none,
we're ready to vote. All in favor
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that that vote is unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
to the governing body will be to
approve. Next item
>> number 20B, consideration of bid number
S-8-26
for an agreement between the city of SH
and Fence Track Incorporated doing
business as full tilt services for the
Dry Creek Restoration Project phase 1
Meadowland Homes and Henderson Ditches
project from the 2023 to 2026 optional
1% sales tax fund.
>> Staff report
Sorry. Sam Bura, uh, city engineering.
Um, before you is a contract with Full
Tilt for phase one of Dry Creek
Restoration. Um, went through the bid
process. Low bid was full tilt. We
reviewed uh the bid. Everything looked
good. It was under uh our engineers
estimate. Everything looks in order.
I can answer any questions you guys
might have.
>> Comments or questions from the
committee?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, through you. Um, thank
you. Are you, Mr. Bur? Great to see you.
Um, is this a contractor we've dealt
with before?
>> I believe so. I believe they did the
work uh at the bellboard and so did a
great job.
>> Further comments or questions from the
committee?
>> Uh, Mr. Chair, I have a question.
>> Sam, good to see you. It's been a while.
I had a looking through that this item.
>> I could not find uh the time frame for
when this project is scheduled to begin
or how long um it's scheduled to last.
Can you just answer that question for me
real quick?
>> Yes, sir. Um
it's going to happen this construction
season. So um after the bid we'll
probably start the process of getting
the contractor um here familiar with the
job and so April time frame probably
starting and then um I can't remember
right off hand but it should be uh
before Frontier Days uh for completion.
>> Excellent. Thank you
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Uh thank you Mr. Chairman through you.
Uh just a point of information so the
public can see it. On page one of three
uh it does say completed by June 30th,
2026.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. I missed that.
>> Any further public comments for
questions from the committee?
Public comment.
Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the
bid an amount not to exceed $458,282.50.
>> Second, Mr. Chairman.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Moody,
seconded by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussion?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Go ahead, Councilman Moody.
>> All right. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
Through you. Um, uh, this is very
important. Uh, two of these are in W
three. I know the Henderson ditch. A
couple of constituents have said when
it's going to be done and one today
actually I showed them and they're very
happy about it. So I know that our
constituents of War 3 will be happy that
we're going to clean up the Henderson
ditch. It's in dire need of it. Thank
you, Mr. Chairman.
>> I echo those sentiments exactly. Thank
you. Ready for a vote. All in favor
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that votes unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
to the governing body will be to approve
this next item
>> number 20 C. Consideration of bin number
S-10-26
for an agreement between the city of
Cheyenne and Mechanical Systems, Inc.
for the North Cheyenne Community Park
drainage improvement project from
development impact fees.
>> Staff report. Mr. Chair, Jason Sanchez,
committee reckoning events. uh before
you and for your consideration is a bid
uh between us and MSI to correct some
drainage issues we're having at
Northshine Community Park. Uh for many
years between pod number four and number
five on the northeast side, we've had
water pooling. That water pooling has
created a an excellent breeding site for
mosquitoes. We have around a little over
1,700 kids that participate in soccer
and it's been a nuisance for a while.
And so we're trying to uh rectify that
problem. This project, if we have your
support, would be completed uh by April
of 2026, and we would be using our park
infrastructure fees to complete the
project. I'll stand by for any
questions.
>> Questions or comments from the
committee?
Any public comment?
Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chairman, um I move to accept uh the
bid in an amount not to exceed um 121,6.
>> It's been moved by Councilman White,
seconded by Councilman Ben Moody. Any
further comments or questions?
Seeing none, can get a vote. All in
favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that vote is unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
to the governing body. Next meeting is
to approve. Next item
>> number 20D. Consideration of bid number
S-11-26
for an agreement between the city of
Cheyenne and Miller and Suns
Construction Incorporated for the
Parsley Boulevard Greenway connectors
project from 2021 specific purpose tax
fund.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chair, I'm Darcy Henden with Dina
Engineering. Um Jeannie Shrednick cannot
be here today. She's ill. She's the
parks and wreck planner. But before you
is a consideration for bids from Dave
Miller and Sons for a greenway project.
When W dot did the partially boulevard
bridge, they put a greenway on the east
side, but they just stopped the greenway
at their edge of their project limits.
So this would extend the greenway to tie
into existing sidewalk um that the city
has on the north on Third Street and to
the south from Jefferson Street to the
greenway um path that exists now. So, we
had seven bids and the um two of them
were lower than the engineers estimate.
So, we're recommending Dave Miller and
Suns for your consideration.
>> Any questions or comments [snorts] on
the committee?
>> Quick comment, Mr. Chair. Uh very happy
for this project to uh finally be in the
works. It's been a long time coming. I
know a lot of folks will be happy to see
that part connected.
>> Absolutely.
Uh, any public comment?
Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chairman,
I uh move to accept the um bid in an
amount not to exceed $228,970.80.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman Wolf, seconded
by Councilman Moody. Any further
comments or discussions?
>> Yes, sir. Council me.
>> All right. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
Through you. I want to echo my uh
colleague on war one online. It needs to
be done. Could also be a safety issue.
So, this will mitigate uh further safety
issues. Thank you.
>> Any further comments from the committee?
Seeing none, can I get a vote? All in
favor signify by saying I. I.
>> I.
>> And that vote is unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
is to approve at the next meeting of the
governing body. Next item, please.
>> Other items for the agenda number A or
letter A. Contract modification number
one to contract number 7777
between the city of Cheyenne and the
Wyoming Department of Transportation for
federal project B231031
Cheyenne Streets US30 Dell Range
Boulevard and Whitney Road, Laramie
County from the 2023 to 2026 optional 1%
sales tax fund.
>> Staff report
Chairman Esel and members of the finance
committee. Um Tom Cobb, city engineer.
As Jennifer has indicated, this has been
this is an amendment to our original
cooperative agreement with WOT. Um this
was signed about 3 years ago, two and a
half to three years ago. Um the
modification is to basically reflect the
revised project costs. Um we've updated
the federal award documentation. We've
got more federal funds available for the
project. And then it clarifies kind of
our responsibilities.
The key changes to the agreement include
the total fiddle participation went from
3.16 million to 6.61 million. Um it also
then as I said before it clarifies the
city's participation that we still have
our proportional share of construction
costs and reimbursement to WOT for
expenses including construction
engineering and indirect costs for IAP
fees which is basically the fees for why
do ch you know as you all know they
charge us for geology for project
management etc. Um that's those are all
updated in this. Um based on the revised
cost estimates, the city's total project
obligation was increased from about
3,986,396
to $7,335,032.
As I indicated to you though, our
federal share went up. So what what
really it did our federal match and
overmatch share went from $824,464
down to $721,867.
So it actually our oper even though the
cost went up, our actual proportionate
share goes down because of the increased
federal funding. With that, um the
amendment I'm asking for is I go ahead
and inflate this because we're due for a
20% overage. So I've I've always
accounted for that upfront. So, this
comes from the 1% optional sales tax 23
to 26 fifth penny. And I'm asking for
the amount to be approved in the amount
of $866,240.
Um, and with that, I'll respectfully
take any questions you might have of me.
>> The comments or questions from the
committee.
Seeing none. Public comment.
See? None. I can I get a motion?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to approve an
amount not to exceed $866,240.
>> Second.
It's been moved by Councilman Moody and
seconded by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussion from the committee?
Seeing none, can I get a motion? That
mean a vote.
>> All in favor say I.
>> I.
Seeing that that motion is uh unanimous
uh votes unanimous the recommendation of
the finance committee will be to approve
at the next meeting of the governing
body. Next item
>> cooperative agreement between the city
of Cheyenne and Larmy County for federal
project B2301031
Cheyenne Streets US30 Del Range
Boulevard and Whitney Road Larmy County
from the 2023 to 2026 optional 1% sales
tax fund. staff report.
>> Good afternoon, uh, Chairman Escoel, um,
members of the finance committee. Tom
Cop, city engineer again. Um, this is
the partner of the cooperative agreement
that we just you just you just
unanimously chose to move forward. So,
this has been, you have never seen
before. This is basically our
reimbursement to the county for charges
that we've already incurred for for the
design and utility relocation costs and
um, the rideway acquisition costs. The
way the agreements were set up with W
dot, it started originally with the
county. So all the costs were then
burdened onto the county. This is our
agreement to reimbursement for those
costs. So based on our current projected
estimates, as I said before, now our
obligation is look at we were looking at
about 2.1 million. So our obligation to
the county is about 2.52 million. Now
again, it's going to come out of the 1%
specific sales tax um for optional sales
tax for fifth penny 23 to 26. Um
let's see if I can break this out any
further. The the the back just in case
you want to see it, there is a breakout
of the cost that I'm showing that for
reimbursement. Um it's in the exhibit on
the very last page in mine. It's exhibit
B.
It basically goes through exactly what
you saw on the other agreement and then
shows where our reimbursement is in the
bottom the highlighted compound in the
bottom. So it's a city of Shine
reimbursement to Larry County. So we
have PE costs which are preliminary
engineering costs in the about a 1.2
million approximately the YCAP fees at
132,000. The rideway costs are about
394,000.
Um the ICAP fees for the rideaway cost
43,000. Our utility relocation was about
300,000 and again I cap fees for white
out to run that at 33,000. So our
reimbursement for the county is
$2,12,874.
Again I've overinflated that for the
account for the one the 120% or so at
1.2. So I'm requesting the amount for
this agreement to be 2 million not to
exceed $2,523,500
for reimbursement for the county for the
project. And with that, take any
questions you might have of me.
>> Questions or comments from the
committee?
Councilman Wolf.
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, thank you for you. Um,
Mr. Cobb, does the county have a
counterpart to you to your job?
>> Chairman throughu to council. Well, yes.
In a roundabout way, the public works
director be Molly Cook.
>> Any further questions or comments from
the committee? Any public comment?
Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, um, I move to approve
an amount not to exceed 2,523,500.
Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
second by Councilman Moody. Any further
discussion?
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. Chairman. Three. Uh,
thank you, everyone. Uh just for the
public to understand that again this is
focused on the roads. You've seen how
US30 is a lot better now than it was a
couple years ago. This is your tax
dollars at work for again the fifth and
sixth penny that you approved. So again
this is definitely important and we got
to make sure that we are good partners
with the county for the roads. Thank
you.
>> Absolutely. Any further discussion from
the committee?
Seeing none. All in favor say I.
>> I. I
>> and that that motion is unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee,
the next meeting of the governing body
will be to approve. That was our last
item today. With that, we are adjourned.